ALEXANDRA ALLEN

heyalexandra.io • 512.632.6057 • aallen632@gmail.com • Austin, TX 78751

SUMMARY

BAS student pursuing a career in Data Science. Skilled in Python, SQL, and machine learning, with project-based experience cleaning, visualizing, and modeling real-world datasets. Excited to uncover insights from data while collaborating with a team and learning from industry professionals.

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

Data Science: Analyzed data using Python, pandas, Seaborn, and related tools while designing informative visualizations in Jupyter Notebook and Tableau.

Machine Learning: Built predictive models using scikit-learn and TensorFlow including preprocessing, model training, and evaluation.

Relational Database Management: Created, edited, queried, and normalized databases using MySQL and PostgreSQL database management systems.

Geographic Information Systems: Processed vector and raster data sets, performed spatial analysis, and designed maps using ArcGIS and QGIS.

ADDITIONAL KNOWLEDGE & SKILLS

- **Web Development:** Built web applications using the MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Node). Used GraphQL and REST APIs and designed web pages with HTML/CSS/Javascript
- Java programming: Focus on multithreading, synchronization, the standard library, and exception handling
- Programming fundamentals: Data structures, debugging, and testing in C++, Java, and Python
- **IDEs:** Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, JupyterLab, PyCharm
- CLI: bash and PowerShell for OS commands and scripting
- Version control systems: Git and GitHub
- **Cybersecurity:** Best practices for information/network/endpoint security

EDUCATION

Austin Community College

2021 - present

Pursuing a Bachelor of Applied Science in Software Development

RECENT WORK EXPERIENCE

Reservationist, Sushi Bar ATX, a fine-dining, Japanese omakase experience

June 2024 - present

- Manage reservations and guest preferences across multiple platforms, requiring a high degree of organization and attention to detail.
- Interact with guests using a professional demeanor while displaying grace under pressure.

Barista, Capital City Bakery, a locally-owned vegan bakery

May 2022 - May 2024

- Developed time management skills making espresso drinks and serving guests in a busy bakery.
- Assisted my team wherever needed, such as helping in the kitchen, washing dishes, or doing admin work.